《哥谭》前情提要
Previously on Gotham...
我需要吸取他的力量
I need to siphon his strength.
等时机一到
So when the time is right,
推翻他的统治
taking over his organization
就会如同戴手套一样轻松
will be like slipping on a glove.
我们不是要偷钱  布奇
The point wasn't to steal that money, Butch.
是要伤到法尔科内
It was to hurt Falcone.
她叫什么名字
What's her name?
塞琳娜・凯尔
Selina Kyle.
她看到了全过程吗
So, she saw everything?
是的
Yes.
她在这里会给布鲁斯少爷带来危险
Her being here will put Master Bruce in great danger.
她也是我们找出杀害我父母凶手的最好的机会
She's also the best chance we have of finding who killed my parents.
你要继续为菲什工作
You are gonna keep working for Fish.
你要告诉我
You are gonna tell me
她说的每一句话
every little thing that she says.
洛夫克拉夫特  我有个目击证人
Lovecraft, I have an eyewitness
能指证你与这起案子有关
who can tie you to the crime,
并指认其他的涉案人员
you and all the others involved.
告诉我  丹特  我杀谁了
So, tell me, Dent-- who did I kill?
托马斯和玛莎・韦恩夫妇
Thomas and Martha Wayne.
本字幕由 YYeTs 人人影视 原创翻译
[WEB&BD版美剧字幕精编者]再加工制作
本人由衷感谢原译作者的无私奉献  并保留所有译作者的信息
如需其它剧集字幕  请登陆新浪微博（http://weibo.com/MJZM100）
或发邮件索取 lj20090303@163.com
你迷路了吗  小姐
You lost, Miss?
这里是韦恩庄园吗
This is Wayne Manor?
是的  但你不该来这儿
Yeah, but not sure you should be here.
你要迷路了  我可以告诉你怎么回去
Point you back to the road if you're lost.
不用  谢谢
No, thanks.
这正是我要来的地方
I am where I need to be.
剖了他
Open him.
翻译：灰灰是菇凉   艾瑞卡   Reginamoon   DustD   木浅薰
翻译：Silence   哥谭直属   夜影章鱼X   草草
时间轴：Kallen   凭陵新月   最可爱的小胖子       后期：宝宝
特效：宝宝          校对&总监：草草
这里绷住
Keep it tight here.
好点了吗
Better?
嗯
Better.
你要真想考验自己
If you want to test yourself,
就该跟我去爬市中心大桥
you should come with me to the Midtown Bridge.
你爬过那桥
You've climbed it?
对  一直爬到顶上
Yeah, to the top.
小年轻都爬到上面去亲热
Kids go up there to make out. All the time.
你愿意的话我可以带你去
I could take you, if you want.
好啊
Okay.
我很乐意
I'd like that.
我先问你个问题
Let me ask you a question.
你在看的那些你爸妈的资料是什么回事
What's up with all the weird homework about your mom and dad?
我想弄明白为什么会发生这样的事
I'm trying to understand why it happened.
没什么为什么可言
There's no why.
坏事常会发生  你得过了这个坎
Bad stuff happens. You-you got to get over it.
也许你是对的
Maybe you're right.
那是当然
Of course I'm right.
你想吻我吗
You want to kiss me?
不  谢谢
No, thank you.
不想吗
No?
我想
I would like to,
但我总不禁觉得你别有用心
but I can't help feeling you have an ulterior motive.
我觉得你不会把我当做合适的恋人
I don't imagine you consider me a suitable romantic partner,
所以你为什么想吻我呢  我想不明白
so why would you want to kiss me? I don't know.
你想太多了  小子
You think too much, kid.
我只是想友善点
I'm just trying to be nice.
无意冒犯  我不觉得你是个友善的人
No offense, you don't strike me as a nice person.
什么意思  我很友善
What do you mean? I'm nice.
我不是说你不是好人  但是你不友善
I don't mean you're not a good person, but you're not nice.
你不太在乎别人
You don't care much for other people.
去你的  没爹娘的
Screw you, orphan.
自己一个人去爬桥吧
Climb the damn bridge on your own.
你好  小姐  有什么能为你效劳的
Yes, hello, Miss. How can I help?
天啊
Oh, dear.
我的车  冲下了路面
My car, it went off the road.
拜托
Please...
请进  快请进
Please come in. Come in at once.
请帮我叫救护车
If you could call an ambulance.
你伤到了哪里
Where exactly are you hurt?
阿尔弗雷德
Alfred.
没事吧
Is everything all right?
是这样  布鲁斯少爷
No, Master Bruce.
这位女士出了车祸
This lady's been involved in a car accident.
跑  快跑
Run. Run!
这儿最好能走出去
This better be a way out.
穿过衣帽间就是以前的仆人走廊
The old servant's hallway, it's through the closet.
我得去帮阿尔弗雷德
But I need to help Alfred!
没时间了
There's no time!
布鲁斯  快走
Bruce, come on!
阿尔弗雷德可能受伤了  我不能抛下他
Alfred might be hurt. I can't leave him.
他让你快跑
He told you to run.
随便你
Fine.
你不走  我走
Stay, but I'm out.
布鲁斯
Bruce!
哥谭
第一季  第十集
当地警方在搜索树林
Local PD is searching the woods,
但目前还没找到布鲁斯或塞琳娜
but so far no sign of Bruce or Selina.
跟我描述下这个女人
What can you tell me about this woman?
她三十出头
Well, she was, uh, early 30s.
还挺能打的
A tasty fighter, actually.
听着  伙计  就是点小伤
Look, mate, it's just a scratch.
快走吧  行不
Shove off, will you?
我还有事要做
I've got stuff to do.
我们有五十个警察在搜索树林
Look, we've got 50 police in the woods,
还有更多在路上找
even more on the roads.
我们得重点调查这个女人和她的同伙
We need to focus on this woman and her people.
关于她你还能告诉我什么
What can you tell me about her?
他们都是职业杀手
They were trained killers.
就是你那个小姑娘把他们引过来的
And your bloody little girl brought them here.
这我们还不能确定
We don't know that yet.
吉姆
Jim.
你一定是阿尔弗雷德・潘尼沃斯了
You must be Alfred Pennyworth.
身手不赖啊
Nice job out there.
看来还不够好
Yeah, well, not nice enough, eh?
这是从死者身上搜出来的
This was taken off the dead guy.
除了这别的什么都没有  没钥匙也没身份证
Nothing else-- no keys, no I.D., nada.
我认得这女孩
Now, I know this girl.
她之前被儿童绑架犯抓走了
She was grabbed by the child snatchers.
而现在居然在韦恩庄园
And now she's getting attacked by assassins
被杀手袭击了
at Wayne freaking Manor?!
这到底怎么回事  伙计
What the hell's going on, compadre?
怎么  你还没告诉他吗
What, you haven't told him?
告诉我什么
Told me what?
韦恩夫妇被害当晚
Selina Kyle was in the alley
塞琳娜・凯尔在那条巷子里
the night the Waynes were murdered.
她看到杀手的长相了
She saw the killer's face.
我的天  别开玩笑了
Oh, for Pete's sake, don't do this to me.
地检官办公室的哈维・丹特
Harvey Dent in the D.A.'s office
在调查迪克・洛夫克拉夫特
is investigating Dick Lovecraft.
他觉得洛夫克拉夫特和韦恩案有关
He thinks that Lovecraft is connected to the Wayne killings.
他放出我们有目击证人的消息
So, he leaked that we had a witness.
他以为这样能吓到洛夫克拉夫特
He thought he could spook Lovecraft.
让他露出马脚
Get him to reveal himself.
计划真厉害啊
Wow, that's a hell of a plan.
效果如何  好极了
How did it work out? Bravo!
我们以为她是安全的
We thought she was safe.
以为没人知道她在这里
We thought no one knew she was here.
你想错了  不是吗  你个呆子
Yeah, well, you were wrong, weren't you, you plank?
他们怎么知道的
How did they know?
这么蠢的计划怎么不告诉我一声
Why didn't you tell me about this foolishness?
因为你肯定会想阻止我
Because you would have tried to stop me.
我当然会阻止你啊  你个白痴
Of course I would tried to stop you, you putz!
你想什么啊
What the hell are you thinking?
韦恩案结了  案子结了
The Wayne case is closed. It is closed!
你明明清楚案子没结
You know damn well it's not closed!
少自以为是了
Don't tell me what I know!
你们两个都给我闭嘴
Will you shut up, the pair of ya!
你们可以待会儿再吵
You can argue later!
现在我们得找到布鲁斯少爷
Right now, we need to find Master Bruce.
好
All right.
要是他们待会儿没回来
If they don't come back soon,
就是去哥谭了
they would have headed to Gotham.
塞琳娜在那儿有安全感
Selina feels safe there.
看你能不能在城里找到她
Good luck trying to find her in the city.
像她那种流浪儿
A street kid like that?
但你会帮我们找到她的  对吗
But you will help us find her, right?
当然会
Yeah, of course I will,
因为我非得发疯
because I have to be crazy.
谢谢  好了
Thank you. All right,
我继续调查洛夫克拉夫特  我会找到他
I'll focus on Lovecraft, I'll find him,
如果他是幕后黑手  我会叫他收手的
and if he is behind this, I'll get him to call off the contract.
你想怎么叫他收手
How you gonna do that?
不知道  会想出办法的
I don't know, I'll think of something.
上街找  好吗
Run the streets, huh?
找你的联系人  干活儿去吧
Focus on your contacts. Go to work.
我跟你去
I'm coming with you.
好吧
All right.
作为一名男仆  你还挺厉害的啊
You're pretty handy for a valet.
管家  伙计
Butler, mate.
我是管家
I'm the butler.
我们得打电话给阿尔弗雷德
We need to call Alfred.
你有看见电话吗
You see any phones?
没有
No.
也许我们应该回我家去
Perhaps we should go back to my house.
如果警察在那里  我们就知道那里是安全的
If the police are there, we'll know it's safe.
是啊  没错
Yeah, right.
警察能保证安全吗
The police will make it safe?
我们总得联系警察啊
We have to contact the police at some point.
有人试图杀你
Someone tried to kill you.
我
Me?
没人知道我在那里
Nobody knew I was there.
那是你家  那些人是想杀你
It's your house; someone wants to kill you.
为什么会有人想要杀我
Why would anyone want to kill me?
一定是因为你那些蹩脚的小调查
Must be all that lame detective work you're doing.
结果还真好  是吧
Paid off good, huh?
开心点
Cheer up.
我们没事的
We're cool.
我们甩掉他们了
We lost them.
我很担心阿尔弗雷德
I'm worried about Alfred.
放松
Relax.
等我把你安全安置在城里
Once I got you safely hidden in the city,
我就去给你找部电话
I'll find you a phone.
谢谢你
Thank you.
很感谢你帮忙
I appreciate your help.
我只是想对你友善点
Just trying to be nice.
法尔科内别墅
马罗尼怎么会知道我的钱在哪里
How did Maroni know where my money was?
什么...
Wha...
这真是个好问题
Well, that's a very good question.
我无意埋怨  但您可以直接打个电话的
Not to criticize, but you could have just called me.
我再问你一次
I'm going to ask you once more.
马罗尼怎么会知道我的钱在哪里
How did Maroni know where I kept my money?
根本没人知道
No one knew.
军械库的抢劫
The robbery at the armory.
不是马罗尼干的
That wasn't Maroni.
我还以为我们是朋友呢
I thought we were friends.
我们达成了共识
We had an understanding.
你告诉我马罗尼的每步动作
You tell me every move Maroni makes.
发生什么事了
What happened?
你是什么时候背叛我的
When did you turn on me?
我没有  法尔科内阁下
Never, Don Falcone.
我发誓  绝对没有
I swear, never.
马罗尼和军械库的抢劫无关
Maroni had nothing to do with the armory job.
否则我会知道的
I would know.
我会告诉您的
I would have told you.
假如不是马罗尼  又是谁
Who was it if not Maroni?
他们又是怎么知道我的钱的
And how did they know about my money?
谢谢你  莉莎
Thank you, Liza.
马上就好了
Won't be long.
我等会儿再来
I'll come back.
我问了你一个问题
I asked you a question.
显然  您这儿有个内奸
Oh, you have a mole, obviously.
玩这套可不是马罗尼的强项  不是吗
Which is not Maroni's forte, is it?
这是别人干的
No, this is someone else.
某个狡猾的人
Someone artful.
某个和您很亲近的人
Someone close to you.
我知道你在说谁
I know who you're going to name.
但是你对菲什的恨意让我怀疑
But your hatred of Fish makes me doubt
你对她的一切指控
anything you say against her.
恕我直言...
With respect...
我不明白您为何还要容忍她
I don't understand why you still tolerate her existence.
她无数次表现出对您的不敬
She has proved her disloyalty a hundred times.
她想要杀您
She wants your head.
半数为我工作的人都有这想法
Like half the people who work for me.
菲什为我赚了很多钱
Fish makes me a lot of money.
我可以对付菲什・穆尼
I can handle Fish Mooney,
或是任何背叛我的混蛋
or whatever son of a bitch did this to me.
告诉我怎么找出奸细
Tell me how to find the mole.
您就交给我吧  法尔科内阁下
You leave that to me, Don Falcone.
这是脏活儿
Dirty work.
我会为您找出奸细的
I'll find your mole for you.
相信我
Trust me...
他绝对是菲什的人
he'll belong to Fish.
拿出证据来
Bring me proof.
我不明白
I don't get it.
你  盖布  不明白
You, Gabe? Not get it?
令人惊奇啊
Quelle surprise.
说说吧  你哪里不明白
What, pray, don't you get?
为什么不告诉法尔科内真相
Why not just tell Falcone the truth?
是那个莉莎背叛了他
It was that Liza girl that betrayed him.
时机  盖布利尔
Timing, Gabriel.
时机就是一切
Timing is everything.
莉莎就是一枚定时炸弹
And Liza is a time bomb.
你就...
Just...
等上一阵子
wait a while.
然后好好看着学着吧
Then watch and learn.
待在那里以防他出现
Stay there in case he shows.
洛夫克拉夫特不在家
Lovecraft isn't at home.
管家从昨天就没见到他了
Housekeeper hasn't seen him since yesterday.
艾伦说他没去办公室
Allen says he didn't come into his office.
他和蒙托亚正在监视那里
He and Montoya are watching it.
杀手怎么知道我的证人在哪的
How did the killers know where to find my witness?
冷静点  这是个胜局
Let's keep calm here. It's a win.
咱们惊了洛夫克拉夫特
We've made Lovecraft panic.
-这是慌张之举  -胜局
- This is a panic move. - A win?!
那两个孩子只身在外
There's two children out there with
被职业杀手追杀
professional assassins coming after them.
布鲁斯和塞琳娜可能会死
Bruce and Selina could end up dead.
我们会让洛夫克拉夫特叫停他们的
We're gonna get Lovecraft to call them off.
他们怎么知道的
How did they know?
我从没告诉过你她的名字
I never told you her name,
更别说她藏在哪里了
let alone where she was hiding,
-所以你不可能...  -我当然不会
- so you couldn't have... - I should say not.
你也没向任何人提过我的名字  对吗
And you never mentioned my name to anyone, right?
没有  我们说好的
No, we agreed.
我不会公开提起任何名字
I didn't mention any names out loud.
不会"公开"提起
No names "out loud"?
那私下呢
What about whispering?
别瞒着我  我会查出来的
Don't hold out on me. I'll know.
作为幕后消息  我泄露了你的名字给几个线人
For deep background, I leaked your name to a couple of select sources.
以增加真实性  我没别的办法
I had to, for credibility!
你是调查韦恩案的警察
You're the Wayne murders cop.
见鬼  他们就是这么找到她的
Damn it! That's how they got to her.
花了这么久才找到她真是奇迹了
I'm surprised it took them this long to find her.
这都是你的错  丹特
This is on you, Dent!
的确是我的错
I'll stipulate mea culpa.
暴揍我  随你便
Kick my ass, be my guest.
但是咱们先找到洛夫克拉夫特
But let's find Lovecraft first
让他叫停那些杀手
and get him to call off the killers.
他不在家  也不在他的办公室
He's not at home, he's not at his office.
他甚至可能离开了高谭
He could've left Gotham.
可能有人窝藏了他
Someone could be hiding him.
洛夫克拉夫特有几处公寓
Lovecraft...has got a couple of condos
是登记在他情妇名下的
that he keeps under his mistress's name.
一个在史蒂文斯堡  另一个在上城区
One up in Stevensburgh and one, uh, uptown.
上城区的那个我去
I'll take the one uptown.
要是这俩孩子出了什么事
If anything's happened to these kids...
我们知道你和一个叫小猫的女孩
We know you ran with a girl
是朋友
called Cat.
她现在很危险
She's in serious danger.
谁又不危险呢
Who isn't, right?
世界就是这么疯狂
Crazy world.
你要多少
How much?
这是100
There's $100.
听着
All right, listen.
我不知道小猫住哪里
I don't know where Cat lives, all right?
她很注重这方面的隐私
She's... private about stuff like that.
但我听说  她找了个新销赃人
But... I heard that she got a new fence,
因为之前那个被抓了
'cause her old one got popped.
他肯定知道哪里能找到她
He'd know where to find her.
这个销赃人是谁
Who's the fence?
我不知道
I don't know.
但我知道谁可能知道
But I know who would know.
是吗  那又是哪位
Oh, yeah? Who's that?!
真是的  阿尔弗雷德  省省吧你
Damn it, Alfred, save your cheese!
我用一摞硬币就能打到他招供
I can beat the truth out of this kid with a roll of quarters!
去问菲什・穆尼
Yo, ask Fish Mooney.
所有销赃人都归她管
She runs all the fences.
抱歉吓到大家了
Forgive me for shocking you,
但允许我给大家解释一下
but let me give you some context here.
我很爱巴尼恩
I loved Bannion.
起家时他就跟着我了
We came up together.
但他应该守好军械库的  可他失败了
But he was supposed to guard the armory, and he didn't.
而且也许  只是也许
And maybe, just maybe,
是他背叛了我
he looked the other way.
我不确定
I don't know.
那我该怎么办呢
So what do I do?
放任不管吗
Let it lie?
老大  我们理解...
Boss, we understand...
不管还有谁参与了  很快  就会祈求
Whoever else was involved will very soon wish
他们死的能像巴尼恩一样痛快
they could die quickly, like Bannion.
现在  我们所有人都得为家族利益着想
In the meantime, all of us must do what's right for the family.
你们每个人的税都要加25%
Each of your tariffs will increase 25%
直到补上储备的空缺
until we've built the reserves again.
无意冒犯  但这有点高吧
No disrespect, that's high.
是有点
A little bit.
你怎么想  菲什  我的要求合理吗
What do you think, Fish? Am I being fair?
我们是一家人
We're family.
有福同享  有难同当
We sink or swim together.
你们都学着菲什点
You could all learn from Fish.
她就很信任我
She trusts me.
你信任我  我就信任你
Trust me, and I'll trust you.
这是双向的
It goes both ways.
吃饭吧
Let's eat.
有电话
There's a phone!
快来
Come on!
我没有硬币
I don't... I don't carry coins.
你有硬币吗
Do you have any coins?
没
Nope.
一个子儿都没
Not a dime.
再说阿尔弗雷德对你有这么重要吗
Why does Alfred matter so much to you anyway?
他不过是你的管家
He's just your butler.
他是我的家人
He's my family.
好运  小子  也许后会有期吧
Good luck, kid. See you around maybe.
什么
What?
-等等  -听着
- Wait! - Look...
那些坏人是冲我来的
those bad guys were there for me.
不是你
Not you.
你不必担心
You have nothing to worry about.
回家吧
Go home.
可是你说
But you said...
我只是想吓唬你
I was just trying to freak you out.
我逗你玩的
I was playing with you.
你逗我玩
You were playing with me?
这也太残忍了吧
That's kind of cruel, isn't it?
是的
Yeah.
听我说
No, look,
你对我的看法没错
you're right about me.
我并不友善
I'm not nice.
不像你
Not like you.
你待人非常友善
You got a nice way about you.
-待人友善  -是的
- "A nice way"? - Yeah.
所以我才说他们的目标是你
That's why I said that thing about you being the target,
这样我们就可以在外多玩一会儿
so, you know, we could hang out a while longer.
我懂了
I see.
好复杂的心理
It's very convoluted reasoning.
随你怎么说
Whatever.
总之  很高兴认识你
Anyhow, it's been cool.
-我要消失了 -你不能这么做
- I'm gonna disappear. - But you can't do that!
-我不是在征求你的意见  -你不能消失
- I wasn't asking. - You can't disappear!
你得和我一起回家
You have to come back home with me.
等戈登警探找到杀害我父母的凶手
When Detective Gordon finds the man who killed my parents,
你得作证
you have to testify.
你真以为会有那一天吗
You really think that was ever going to happen?
别幼稚了  B
Grow up, B.
不  别跳  你跳不过来的
No, don't! You won't make it!
救命
Help.
你疯了
You're crazy.
请别再跑了  我喘不过气了
Please don't run off again. I'm out of breath.
好吧  小子
Okay, kiddo.
你赢得这资格了
You earned it.
要跟我待在一起也行
You want to hang with me, that's cool,
但是在我的地盘就要听我的
but my world, my rules.
照我说的做
You do what I say.
遵命  女士
Yes, ma'am.
我为什么不能给阿尔弗雷德
Why can't I call Alfred
或戈登警探打电话  向他们报平安呢
or Detective Gordon to let them know I'm okay?
因为我们现在消失了
Because we're disappearing.
要像烟一样无迹可寻
You got to be like smoke.
烟可不会打电话报平安
Smoke doesn't make phone calls.
-这是什么地方  -跳蚤市场
- What is this place? - The Flea.
就像流浪儿的购物中心
It's like the mall for street kids,
还没有难听的音乐
without the crappy music.
天黑之前  我们在这里都很安全
We'll be safe here till dark.
法尔科内让我很紧张
Falcone's making me nervous.
如果他怀疑是我们炸毁了他的钱
If he suspects it was us who blew up his money,
那他为什么还不行动
why hasn't he made a move?
因为他对此不确定
'Cause he can't be sure.
还有另外十个人可能做这事
There are ten other people who could have done this.
那现在怎么办
So what now?
照原计划行事
You're going to stick to the plan.
你去联系萨维亚诺和图斯基
You're gonna reach out to Saviano and Turski.
他们俩都很生气税率涨了
They are both very angry that their taxes have been raised,
也担心自己会落得巴尼恩的下场
and they're worried about ending up like Bannion.
他们准备好了
They're ready.
老家伙在把他的手下赶到我这边
The old man is herding his sheep toward me.
收到  老大
You got it, boss.
好
All right.
先生们  你们好啊
Hello, gentlemen.
我们很忙  哈维  你明年再来吧
Busy day, Harvey. Come back next year.
对天发誓  布奇
Hand to God, Butch,
我会比水手上岸休假还快
I'll be quicker than a sailor on shore leave.
我们在找一个小偷
Thief we're tracking down.
眼熟吗  人称"小猫"
Look familiar? Goes by "Cat."
不认识
Nope.
也许菲什认识她
Maybe Fish knows her.
菲什谁都认识
Fish knows everyone.
菲什很忙
Fish is busy.
她和你们的一个销赃人有来往  是个新人
She works with one of your fences, a new guy.
销赃人是什么
What's a fence?
拜托  布奇  友善一点
Come on, Butch. Be nice.
这很重要
This is important.
菲什呢
Where's Fish?
我说了  她很忙
I told you, she's busy.
我以前认识一个叫布奇的伙计
I once knew a fella called Butch.
他是白教堂人
Yeah, he was a Whitechapel lad.
我们这么叫他  但他其实不是个壮汉
Now, we called him Butch, you see, 'cause he wasn't.
只是为了激怒他
It was a wind-up.
取笑他
It was like a joke name.
事实上  他是个讨厌的小个子
In fact, he was a horrible little toe rag.
怎么
What?
我搞不懂  你是...在恐吓我吗
I can't tell. Are-are you... are you threatening me?
他是在恐吓我吗
Is he threatening me?
是吗
Yeah?
你不是...
You can't...
好了  这个菲什在哪
Now... where is this Fish?
就在这里
Right here.
吵什么呢
So... what's the fuss?
他们闹着玩呢
They're just fooling around.
我们在找个女孩
We're looking for this girl,
一个街头小偷  叫小猫
a street thief, goes by Cat,
和你一个销赃人有来往
works with one of your fences.
有点眼熟  为什么这么急
Looks familiar. What's the urgency?
有职业杀手在找她
Professional killers are looking for her.
职业杀手
Professionals, huh?
这不会是洛夫克拉夫特的目击证人吧
This wouldn't be the Lovecraft witness, now would it?
你怎么知道的
How'd you know?
坊间传言
Streets talk.
利用她去吓唬洛夫克拉夫特
Using her to scare Lovecraft.
她看见了杀害韦恩夫妇的人
She saw the Waynes' killer,
据称如此
supposedly.
是的
Yeah.
你来是想让我帮你找到她  是吧
And you're here because you want me to help you find her, don't you?
是的
Yes.
哈维
Harvey...
我凭什么帮你找她呢
Why in the world would I help you find her, of all people?
她和布鲁斯・韦恩在一起  女士
She has Bruce Wayne with her, miss.
真的吗
Really?
是的  女士
Yes, miss.
我是阿尔弗雷德・潘尼沃斯
I'm Alfred Pennyworth.
是他的法定监护人
I'm the boy's legal guardian.
-很高兴认识你  -我也是
- Very pleased to meet you. - Likewise.
穆尼女士  我们需要你的帮助
Miss Mooney, we need your help.
阿尔弗雷德  我很想帮助你
Well, you see, Alfred, I would love to help you,
但那会损害我的个人利益
but it would infringe upon my personal interests.
我为什么要那么做呢
And why would I do that?
你拥有深邃的...目光
You have a very eloquent... gaze,
恕我冒昧  穆尼女士
if I may say so, Miss Mooney.
我能看出  你不会为
And I can see that you're not a woman that would
一己私利  不顾道义
let petty self-interest outweigh... honor.
和慈悲
And compassion.
我去打几个电话
I'll make some calls.
但你可别忘了我的好意
But remember this kindness.
好多了
Much better.
是吗
Really?
我说不准
I'm not sure.
你看上去挺狠的
You look badass.
真的
No lie.
你好啊  小猫
Hey, Cat.
艾薇
Ivy...
你怎么来这儿了
what are you doing here?
你最近都干吗了  我还以为...
What have you been up to? I thought...
是啊  进了少管所
Yeah, Juvie caught me.
我被收养去了州北
I got adopted upstate.
那家人不好吗
Didn't take?
都是好人  就是他们想要我剪头发  穿戴整齐
Good people-- they wanted me to cut my hair, dress nice.
我认得你
I know you.
你是马里奥・佩珀的女儿
You're Mario Pepper's daughter.
我是  你是谁
Yes. Who are you?
我是布鲁斯・韦恩
I'm Bruce Wayne.
是啊  当然
Yes, you are.
亿万富翁布鲁斯・韦恩
Billionaire Bruce Wayne.
态度好点  艾薇
Stay cool now, Ivy.
我态度挺好的  你说这个干什么
I am cool. Why are you telling me that?
你干吗对我指手画脚的
Why are you telling me what to do?
我没有啊  我就是说
I'm not. I'm just saying,
我不希望你生他的气
I don't want you to get mad at him.
他是个朋友
He's a friend.
我生他的气做什么
Why would I get mad at him?
又不是他的错  是吧
It's not his fault, is it?
是你杀了我父亲吗
Did you kill my father?
是你逼我母亲割腕的吗
Do you make my mother cut her wrists?
不是
No.
是别人  有人害死我父母  但不是他
Somebody did-- somebody did, but not him.
你怎样  你还好吗
How you doing? You doing okay?
我挺好  你呢
I'm okay. And you?
我也挺好  我看起来如何
I'm doing great. How do I look?
你看起来不错
You look good.
你看见销赃人克莱德了吗
Have you seen Clyde the fence around?
看见了  他在奈何岛的工厂那边
Yeah, he's working out of the Factory on the Narrows.
他挺可爱的  是不是
He's cute, isn't he?
没错  挺可爱  多谢  艾薇
Yes, he is. Uh, thanks, Ivy.
见到你真好  我们得赶紧去见克莱德了
Good to see you. Uh, we got to go run and see Clyde.
是吗  那好吧  回见
Oh. Okay, fine. Bye, then.
往前走
Keep moving.
她就是个小女孩而已
She's just a little girl.
你这么怕她做什么
Why are you so scared of her?
她就是让人害怕  别回头
Because she's scary. Don't look back.
哥谭市警局
GCPD!
放下枪
Drop it.
踢过来
Kick it over.
你因涉嫌谋杀被捕了
You're under arrest. Conspiracy to commit murder.
谋杀  我  还谋杀
Murder? Me, murder?
你在说什么呢
Look, what are you talking about?
你派人刺杀塞琳娜・凯尔
You put a hit out on Selina Kyle.
不  不是我
No, not me.
刺杀她的人也来要我的命了
The same people that came after her came after me, too.
他们在大街上袭击我
Th-They attacked me on the street.
不然你以为我藏什么呢
Why do you think I'm hiding in here?
他们追杀你做什么
Why would they come after you?
还能为了什么
Why do they ever come?
我知道得太多了
Because I know too much.
少废话  你究竟怕谁
Cut the crap. Who are you so scared of?
你真是什么都不知道  是不是
You have no idea, do you?
你以为我是幕后大佬
You think I'm the big wheel.
到了关键的时候  小子
When it comes to the crunch, kid,
我跟你一样  什么都不是
I'm nobody, just like you.
真正掌握这城市的人
A-And the people who really, truly run this city,
他们看着你到处忙活  寻求正义
they're watching you huff and puff and run around crusading,
他们只会嘲笑你
and they are laughing at you.
你深陷迷宫
You're so deep in the maze,
根本看不清大局
you can't see over the wall.
跟我说点我不知道的
Tell me something I don't know.
我的箱子  在床下  有文件
My briefcase, under the bed. Files.
去拿
Go.
就在韦恩夫妇被杀之前
Right before the Waynes got killed,
有人操纵韦恩集团股票
there was a run on Wayne Enterprises stock.
就像是有人知道要有坏事发生
Like somebody knew something bad was gonna happen.
所以我就觉得我该分杯羹
So I figured I deserved a cut.
于是便开始调查
So I started digging.
我是为那人而来
I've come for that man.
你不必受伤
You need not get hurt.
刚刚真好玩
That was nice.
找时间再玩一次吧
Let's do it again sometime.
说
Yeah?
菲什有俩孩子的线索
Fish got a lead on the kids,
奈何岛一个叫工厂的地方
at a place on the Narrows called The Factory.
据说小猫的销赃人叫克莱德
Word is, Cat used a fence named Clyde.
他就在那里  我们这就过去
He hangs there. We're on our way now.
阿尔弗雷德  我们走吧
Alfred, let's go.
菲什  谢谢
Fish, thank you.
你欠我个人情
You owe me.
我谁不欠啊
Who don't I owe?
洛夫克拉夫特先生
Mr. Lovecraft?
糟糕
No, no, no, no, no.
我是戈登警探
This is Detective Gordon.
警号231611
Badge number 23-16-11.
安提俄克街1257号发现尸体
Reporting body at 1257 Antioch.
小猫  好姑娘
Cat! My baby!
-克莱德  -哎呀
- Hey, Clyde. - Well...
你给我带来了什么
what have you got for me?
东西不错啊
Sweet swag.
跟平时那些破烂不一样
Not your usual junk.
人往高处走嘛
Moving on up.
这是哪来的
Where'd you get this?
你买故事还是东西
You want a story or the swag?
多少钱
How much?
一千
Thousand bucks.
得了吧  你别闹了
Please. Give me a break.
你知道这都是最低价了
That's rock-bottom, you know it is.
50块
Fifty bucks.
Fifty?
这可是真正的金笔
This pen is real gold,
那个玉吊坠可是古董
and that's an antique jade netsuke.
单那一个都值两千
It's worth $2,000 on its own.
这位伶牙俐齿的小家伙是谁
And who is this well-spoken little... dude?
别管他是谁了
Never mind who he is.
500块打底了
Look, 500 is rock-bottom.
你为什么这么跟我耗
Why are you wasting my time?
放松
Relax.
我们肯定可以...达成协议
I'm sure we can... make a deal.
算了  我们去别处
No, thanks. We'll go elsewhere.
冷静  小猫
Cool down, Cat.
否则我们把你小伙伴的眼珠子戳出来
Or we'll poke your little friend's eyes out.
这就对了
That's it.
放松
Relax.
我有几个朋友要来  他们肯定想见到你
I've got some friends coming over who would just love to meet you.
都齐了
It's all there.
别紧张
Don't look so anxious.
你们看上去挺爱动手的
Yeah, well, um... you guys are kind of sporty.
她人呢
Where is she?
在楼上
She's upstairs.
最好是如此
She better be.
找件重物来
Find me something heavy.
全哥谭只有我一个人知道等后援吗
Am I the only one in this damn town who waits for backup?!
布鲁斯
Bruce!
跟上去
Follow!
阿尔弗雷德在哪
Where's Alfred?
里面
He's in there.
上
Go!
趴下
Down!
你女朋友呢
Where's your girlfriend?
我不知道
I have no idea.
别逼我伤你
Don't make me hurt you.
你不是我的任务
You're not on the contract.
她走了
She's gone.
给你点建议  孩子
Some advice, kid:
别把勇敢当聪明
don't ever mistake bravery for good sense.
阿尔弗雷德
Alfred.
没想到会在这里见到你
Fancy seeing you here.
你没事吧
You all right?
我没事
I'm fine.
你呢
How are you?
你吓死我了  布鲁斯少爷
You really scared me, Master Bruce.
如果你死了
If you die...
这年头还有谁雇管家啊
who employs butlers anymore?
谢天谢地
Oh, thank God.
洛夫克拉夫特是社会栋梁
Lovecraft was a beloved pillar of this community.
尽心服务哥谭
A dedicated servant of Gotham.
我该怎么跟媒体说
So, what do I tell the media, huh?
有建议吗
Any ideas?
他是个骗子
He was a crook.
我们差点抓到他了
We nearly had him.
杀他的人  是如果他能活着作证
And he was killed by whoever he would have implicated
会指认的人
if he had lived to testify.
就这么说
Say that.
抱歉我无法采取你的办法
Forgive me if I can't get behind your approach.
杀他的是你的枪
It was your gun.
我没杀他
I didn't kill him.
总的来说  我相信你
On balance, I believe you-- on balance.
但自杀更加干净利落...
But suicide is much cleaner...
不是自杀  是他杀
It wasn't suicide, it was murder!
就是自杀
It was suicide!
他被你无休止的询问逼疯了
He went mad under your relentless questioning,
制服了你
overpowered you
用你的枪自杀了
and killed himself with your gun.
不要给我别的说辞
And don't tell me otherwise.
怎么样  律师
What do you say, counselor?
我听您的  詹姆斯市长
I'm at your disposal, Mayor James.
抱歉让您担心了
I'm sorry if we've caused you any disquiet.
"担心"
"Disquiet."
你两个自大的小丑
You arrogant clowns.
你们在攻击这座城市的根基
You're hacking away at the very foundations of this city.
想扳倒我
Trying to take me down!
真该把你俩塞进麻袋
Should have the both of you stuffed in a sack
丢进河里
and thrown in the river.
但我不能那么做
But I can't do that.
找两个替罪羊太慌张了
Two scapegoats would look like panic.
但你们有一个要倒霉的  记住我的话
But one of you is going down, mark my words.
先生  不该这样
Sir, that's not right.
闭嘴吧
Hush.
不会是你的  丹特
It's not you, Dent.
当然是戈登先生
Obviously, it's Mr. Gordon.
先生  我抗议
Sir, I protest.
但不会逼得太紧
But not too much.
瞧  丹特律师
You see, Counselor Dent
就知道守规矩
knows how to walk the line.
他知道极限在哪
He knows where the edge is.
而你呢  戈登先生
You, Mr. Gordon,
你不知道极限在哪
do not know where the edge is.
詹姆斯市长
Mayor James.
去你妈
Kiss my ass.
迪克・洛夫克拉夫特的自杀是个天大的惨剧
Dick Lovecraft's suicide is a terrible, terrible tragedy.
对抗一位热血过头的警察
Fighting the trumped-up charges
捏造的指控令他难以承受
of an overzealous police officer was too much for him.
我保证  迪克
You have my word, Dick.
这名警察已经受到了责罚
This officer is being dealt with.
阿卡姆精神病院
Arkham Asylum?
去给疯子做保安
A security guard for nut-jobs?
罪犯疯子  没错
Criminal nut-jobs, yeah.
你要接受吗
Are you taking the assignment?
不是这个就得辞职了
It's that or quit.
那就辞职啊
So quit.
他们就希望我辞职
That's what they want me to do.
该死  吉姆
Damn, Jim.
不管你接下来的搭档是谁
Whoever your next partner is,
不论是男是女  肯定比我好对付
he or she will be a lot easier than me.
爱德
Ed.
戈登警探  我听说你要受罚被革职了
Detective Gordon, I hear you've been thrown out in disgrace.
是这样吗
Is this true?
是的
Yeah, it is.
我要给上面写信
I'm gonna write a letter to the boss.
行啊
You do that.
我该写给谁
Which boss should I write to?
不用了  爱德
Forget it, Ed.
我就是倒霉
That's the breaks, huh?
你保重
You take care.
或许你该把他带上
Maybe you should take him with you.
如果他走了你会想他的
You'd miss him if he was gone.
才不会呢
No, I wouldn't.
回头让我请你喝酒吧
Let me buy you a drink sometime.
回头的
Soon.
你的安保系统还是这么差劲
Your security still sucks.
没人想找我麻烦
No one's hunting for me.
我以为见不到你了
I didn't expect to see you again.
我还没道别呢
Never said good-bye.
是啊
No, we didn't.
我不想无礼啊
Didn't want to be rude.
能见到你很高兴
It-it's good to see you.
给
Here.
谢谢  但你可以留着的
Thank you, but you could keep this.
你比我更需要
You need it more than I do.
不了  我们之间还是坦坦荡荡的吧
Nah, let's keep things honest between us.
这个我要留着
I'm keeping this one anyway.
在聊天呢  布鲁斯少爷
Having a little chat, Master Bruce?
就是在自言自语
Thinking out loud.
好吧
Right.
嗯  当然了
Right. Of course you were.
要我替你拿着吗
Shall I take that for you?
这老房子少了她
The old house seems very quiet...
好冷清  不是吗
without her, doesn't it?
是啊
Yes, it does.
阿卡姆精神病院
如需其它字幕  请登陆新浪微博[WEB&BD版美剧字幕精编者]
或发邮件 lj20090303@163.com